nbr.co.nz 2018-02-18

# Privacy Policy | The National Business Review

By using this site, you agree to the Privacy Policy of National Business Review. If you do not agree to the Policy, please do not use this site. National Business Review examines its privacy policy periodically and reserves the right, at its discretion, to modify or remove portions of this policy at any time. This page should be reviewed periodically so that you are updated on any changes. If you want to communicate with us about our policy, please write to us at:

Fourth Estate Holdings (2012) Limited  
Level 3, Achilles House  
8 Commerce Street,  
Auckland 1140, NZ,  
PO Box 1734, Shortland Street  
Auckland 1140,  
or email us at [customerservices@nbr.co.nz](mailto:customerservices@nbr.co.nz).

NBR, which operates the Internet site located at [www.nbr.co.nz](http://www.nbr.co.nz/) recognises the importance of protecting the privacy of personally identifiable information collected about visitors to our sites. As a general policy, no personally identifiable information, such as your name, address or email address, is automatically collected from visitors to our sites. Personally identifiable information about visitors to our sites is collected only when knowingly and voluntarily submitted. We may collect certain non-personal information to optimise our Web pages for your computer (i.e., the identity of your Internet browser, the type of operating system you use, your IP address and the domain name of your Internet service provider). We may use such non-personal information for internal purposes, including but not limited to improving the content of our sites.

In those instances when we do collect personally identifiable information, the following policies apply:

**Notice**

NBR will notify you when we are collecting personally identifiable information about you and how we intend to use it. For example, we may need to collect such information to provide you with information or a product you requested, in connection with contest entry forms or for billing purposes, or in connection with community postings such as chat and bulletin boards.

Sometimes NBR engages in activities with business partners and sponsors with whom personal information is jointly collected or shared. We will try to make it clear at the time of collection who is asking for and/or sharing your information. In situations where your information will be shared, it is recommended that you also review the privacy policy of our business partner or sponsor.

**Use and Security**

Personally identifiable information that visitors submit to our sites is used only for the purpose for which it is submitted unless we disclose other uses in this Privacy Policy or at the time of collection. Such other uses may include sending you information or materials we think you will find interesting, or sharing the information with NBR's advertisers and reputable business partners. However, at the time of collection, you will have the option of instructing us not to send you additional information or share your personal information with third parties. NBR not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of our business partners.

National Business Review may use reputable third parties to manage activities available on our sites including, but not limited to, sweepstakes, contests, statistical analysis, or chats. These parties may have access to personally identifiable information submitted by visitors who participate in those activities. Similarly, we may contract with third parties to handle the fulfilment of subscriptions or requests for information you submit to our sites, such as sending you a newsletter. In most instances, National Business Review instructs these third parties to use personally identifiable information only for the specific purpose for which it is collected, and not to sell, market or transfer such information to other entities. If National Business Review obtains personal information that has been collected from you by a third party, including our business partners, this Privacy Policy nonetheless governsNBR's use of that information.

Please remember that any information posted as a reader response (e.g., letter to the editor) becomes public information. You should use caution when sharing information as any of it can be collected and used by people you may not know. Users under the age of 18 should be particularly careful not to divulge any personal information. While National Business Review strives to protect and respect your privacy, we can not guarantee the security of any information you disclose in such a communication and you do so at your own risk.

National Business Review may use personally identifiable information in aggregate form to make our sites better and more responsive to the needs of our visitors. This statistical compilation and analysis of information may also be used by National Business Review or provided to others, in aggregate, for marketing, advertising or research purposes.

If at any time after submitting your personal information to our sites you would no longer like to receive information from us, simply follow the "unsubscribe" directions at the end of any email communication you receive.

Personal information may be disclosed in special situations where National Business Review has reason to believe that doing so is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against anyone damaging, injuring, or interfering (intentionally or unintentionally) with NBR's rights, property, users, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. Also, National Business Review may reveal information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

National Business Review maintains appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of personally identifiable information submitted to our sites, and periodically reviews and updates its security measures in light of current technologies. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure. Although National Business Review strives to protect your personal information, we can not ensure or warranty the security of any information you may transmit to us or from our online products and services. This is done so at your own risk. Once we do receive your transmission, however, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. Should credit card information be required as part of any interaction, industry standard encryption is used.

**Cookies**

Cookies are data that a Web site transfers to an individual's hard-drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies, which are an industry standard used by most Web sites, including those operated by NBR, can facilitate a user's ongoing access to and use of a site. They allow us to track usage patterns and to compile data that can help us improve our content and target advertising. National Business Review does not save passwords or credit card information within Cookies, nor are our Cookies programs of the sort that can cause damage to a user's systems or files. If you do not want information collected through the use of Cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to deny or accept the Cookie feature. But you should note that Cookies may be necessary to provide you with features such as merchandise transactions or registered services, and to facilitate entry to the main sections of the site.

In order to improve our user's website experience, and for improved advertising purposes, NBR.co.nz makes use of Google advertising cookies which collect non-individually identifiable information about how users browse our site. If you would like you can [opt-out of Google Analytics Advertising Features](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

**Links to Third Party and Co-Branded Sites**

National Business Review has established relationships with reputable business partners that allow visitors to our Internet sites to link directly to sites operated by these partners. These sites may collect personal information from you that may be shared with NBR. As noted above, this Privacy Policy will apply to any personal information we obtain in this manner.

National Business Review chooses its advertisers and business partners carefully. However, National Business Review is not responsible for the content or practices of Web sites operated by third parties that are linked to our sites. These links are meant for the user's convenience only. Links to third party sites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement or approval by National Business Review of the content, policies or practices of such third party sites. Once you have left a National Business Review site via such a link, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party site.

National Business Review sites may also be linked to Web sites operated by companies affiliated with NBR. Visitors to those sites should refer to their separate privacy policies and practices.

NBR may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to·not having this information used by these companies,[ click here.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)
